Capka has just released the most insane
AI video maker and it's free for
everybody. So, if you're thinking about
creating some faceless AI content or
you're thinking about starting a brand
new YouTube channel, listen up because
it's now easier than ever and you can do
it all for free. So, in this video, I'm
going to show you what I've created and
then I'm going to give you a full run
through of how to use this new exciting
AI video maker tool. Now, before we get
started, I would recommend downloading
the Capka app for desktop using the link
in the description below. As I said,
it's completely free of charge and gives
you the maximum features. Now, once
you've downloaded it, you'll be able to
access the AI video maker here. So, then
here is the AI video I created, and it
took me no longer than 10 minutes to
make. So, let's play it. Here are five
incredible facts about sharks that you
definitely haven't heard of before.
There are over 500 species of sharks in
the world's ocean and they come in all
shapes and sizes. But did you know that
there is a shark that can go from the
size of a pin head to the size of a full
grown? Now, as you may or may not know,
I actually used to run an Animal Fact
channel, which I have since retired, but
this video would have been absolutely
perfect for that. So, now I will show
you exactly how you can create something
like this, too. But before that, for
those of you who aren't really yet
familiar with what CupK is, it's a
powerful all-in-one video editor made by
the creators of Tik Tok. It's well known
for being beginner friendly, super
intuitive, and packed with
professionalgrade features. Whether
you're editing on your phone or your
desktop, Cap Cut lets you create
highquality videos with ease. And now
they've taken things to the next level
with their brand new AI video maker. And
this new AI tool is able to generate
scripts, images, AI avatars, clips,
subtitles, and even music, all powered
by AI with easy workflows, fast video
generation, and effortless creativity.
You simply just enter a basic video
idea, and it will generate a highquality
ready to publish AI video in minutes.
Now, whether you're a beginner or a
professional, this tool will be your
ultimate assistant for effortless video
creation. So without further ado, let me
show you exactly how to create these AI
videos. Okay, so if you follow the link
in the description, you'll be brought to
this screen here, which is basically the
website of Cap Cut, and it's a free AI
video generator. And what I'm going to
suggest you do is click up here on
download, download the app, and then
from the app, I'll show you exactly how
to use it. So once you've downloaded the
app and you've logged into your account,
this is obviously the screen you're
going to be met with when you first
upload it. Now, what we're going to want
to do is click on here, the AI video
maker. So, if you click into that,
you're then going to be brought to this
screen here. So, this is like the
standard interface. You've got welcome
to the free all-in-one AI video maker.
We've got new project or you can use
these down here, which is instant AI
video, which we want. Brainstorm with
AI, which is really cool because it lets
you like brainstorm ideas, find
information, and create compelling
scripts within the snap. Then, avatar
video, then match media to script with
one click. Now, you get all of this
within this part here. So, we don't need
to click into these individually, but
they're just cool to have if you wanted
to go straight into one of those. And
then down here, we have simplify
creation with AI templates, which I'll
show you afterwards. These are great for
creating reals, Tik Toks, and YouTube
shorts. And I'll run through how to use
one of these templates afterwards. But
for now, I'm going to show you how to
recreate that shark video I did so you
guys can create some long format videos,
too. So, just click new project, and
then you're going to be brought to this
screen here. So, step one is craft your
script. Now, this looks very blank and
bare, which is intentional. They want to
keep it as simple as possible. So, here
you either have the option to enter a
script if you've already got one, or
create one. So, there's no need for chat
GBT anymore. You can do everything in
here, which is super helpful. So, I'm
going to show you how to create one
within the actual Cap Cut AI script
generator. So, click on that one, and
then you're going to have create script,
topic, key points, duration, writing
style, and more requirements. So, we'll
go through these bit by bit. So for me,
I want to create a video on shark facts.
Now I put the topic of shark facts up
there so they know what's what. So in
this little box here, this is where you
describe the actual video you want to
create. Now the more information you put
in here, the better the script, but you
can just put a few words in and it will
still give you a proper script. So enter
your key points or links. You can even
link websites or like let's say research
papers to help your script in there if
you want to. And then they will turn it
into a script for you. So for me, I'm
going to put create an engaging video
based on five interesting shark facts.
Include the tiger shark, the bull shark,
the hammerhead shark, the great white
shark, and the whale shark. So
obviously, I'm not given that much
information. I just want a video on
shark facts. And I want those specific
shark facts included. Then down here, we
have duration. So 1 minute, 3 minute, 5
minute, 10 minute. So this is crazy
because caput will literally create a
full 10-minute long script for you just
using those key points if you wanted it
to. Now, whenever you go to chat and be
like, "Can you make me a 10-minute long
script?" Usually, it's only a few
hundred words. Like, it can never really
get that timing correct. Whereas this
one does. It does it perfectly. Now, for
the purpose of this video, I'm just
going to select 3 minutes because we
don't need a 10-minute long video. Like,
I don't have that much time to show you.
And then down here, we have mimic
writing style. So, if you already have a
YouTube channel full of YouTube videos
and you have a particular writing style,
you can basically copy the old scripts
from your other videos, input it here.
So then Capkut will match the script
writing for this new script to your
current writing style. So everything is
like on brand and everything matches. So
now the next one down here is more
requirements. So here I always put make
sure the first 10 seconds which is the
hook are as engaging as intriguing as
possible because you guys you know by
now that the hook is everything. So as
long as we can make those first few
sentences as engaging as possible we
should be on to winner. So once you're
happy with all of this like that's not
much like detail at all. All I've just
said, shark facts, five shark facts,
make it engaging, 3 minutes long,
create. Let's see what it gives us. So,
within 30 seconds, it's just created
this entire script here. So, get ready
to dive into the fascinating world of
sharks with five incredible shark facts
that will leave you speechless. From
tiger shark unique stripe pattern to
whale sharks gigantic size, these sharks
are truly remarkable creatures. Then we
got here number five. We got number
four. The tiger shark is known for its
ferocious appetite that will eat almost
anything. Number two, we have the bull
shark is one of the most aggressive
shark species and is responsible for
many attacks on humans. Number one, and
then the end bit there. So, just go
through and make sure you're happy with
the entire script. And once you are,
click use. And then we have this entire
script ready to go. From there, once
you're happy with that, then we need to
click on scenes. So, we could select
like a talking head avatar that will
basically read off this entire script.
And you have over a hundred different
avatars to choose from. You've got like
a shake, you've got like an old man
there, you've got like a nudes
presenter. There's so many on there, but
I'm not going to use that now. I'm going
to go straight to voice here. So, this
is where I decide on the actual voice
over. So, again, you've got like over a
hundred different voices you can use,
all for free. And now, it's time to
choose one. So, it's just a case of
literally going through and playing
them. Welcome to creating voiceover. So,
that one's like the very standard AI
voice you probably hear all the time.
So, I won't go for that one for now. I
want like a nice energetic softspoken
maybe American or English accent too.
Welcome to creating voiceovers. That's
not too bad. Already it's a little bit
boring. Let's go down here. Welcome to
creating voiceovers. Bit slow. Welcome
to creating voiceovers. That's exactly
what we want. Energetic. It says excited
man. It's in English and it's got an
American accent. Welcome to creating
voiceover. So that's the one I want. So
what I'm going to do is highlight that
one and click apply to all scenes. And
then what it's going to do is split
script here. So as you can see here,
you've got like big paragraphs. Those
big paragraphs are actually really hard
for AI voiceovers to read. So what it
will do, it will break it down into
individual sentences like this. And then
it just makes it so much easier for the
actual AI voice over to like read it
through and make sure it doesn't make
any mistakes. So yeah, within within
literally about 10 seconds after me
saying that, we're already done. So
let's give this a play. Now, get ready
to dive into the fascinating world of
sharks with five incredible shark facts
that will leave you speechless. From the
tiger shark's unique striped pattern to
the whale shark's gigantic size, these
sharks are truly remarkable creatures.
Now, I'm really, really happy with that.
The voiceover is perfect. So, now we've
got the entire voice over done for the
entire video. All we need to do is click
on media. So, here we have three
different options. You got generative AI
media, you got match your media, and
then you got match stock media. So
generative AI media is where Capkut's
own AI will like literally generate
brand new media for you based on the
script you give it. Then you got match
your media. So if you've got your own
videos or your own stock footage that
you've uploaded to the app, then you can
use that and basically it will scan all
of your media and pick up the best
videos related to the script or match
stock media, which is a really cool one.
So this is where like Capka has an
insane amount of stock footage in their
stock footage library. So what it will
do if you click on match stock media, it
will comb through this entire script,
pick out the keywords. So like tiger
shark, you've got hammerhead shark.
It'll pick out all of those keywords and
then scan its entire stock footage
library and find videos that match those
keywords. So it takes all of the hard
work out of your hands and takes it onto
the actual AI. So, I'm going to click on
match stock media because I personally
like the realistic videos that are
actual real. They've been shot by
someone like a human as opposed to
generative AI media. I will show that
afterwards, but for now, I'm going to
click on match stock media. Okay, so
that took literally two to three minutes
to make and now we've got this entire
like video all done for us. So, what
it's done is it's found stock footage
and matched it with each line you see
here. So, let's give it a play and let's
see what you think. Get ready to dive
into the fascinating world of sharks
with five incredible shark facts that
will leave you speechless. From the
tiger shark's unique striped pattern to
the whale sharks gigantic size, these
sharks are truly remarkable creatures.
So, I'm actually really happy that I
think it's turned out really really
well. Now, you have so much capabilities
of editing like pretty much like
everything here. You can either like
rewrite all this using that thing there.
You can change the actual voice over or
you can like replace this. Say you
didn't like this scene, you can replace
it. Now what you can do is you can click
on stock media. So you can type in let's
say shark here and browse their actual
stock footage. Or you can go on AI
media. So let's go on AI media. Let's
say you prefer generative AI media. So
this one let's say a visually
captivating scene showing whale shark
and I want it realistic 16x9 and then
click generate. So you could go through
and do this with the entire film if you
wanted to. But like I said, for me
personally, I actually like the stock
footage. So I prefer to go for that one.
But if you wanted the actual AI
generative stuff, then you've got it all
here. So I could like add let's say this
one to the scene and then click on add
to scene. And then now we've got let's
start it again. Get ready to dive into
the fascinating world of sharks with
five incredible shark facts. So there
you go. You could go through every
single scene here and replace it with
new stock footage, your own footage, or
get the generative AI media to do it for
you. So, once you're happy with all of
the scenes and all the voice over and
everything like that, then you go down
to elements. Now, this is where you can
see the captions. As you can see here,
you've got like the captions on here as
standard, but these are a bit boring.
They're not very like intriguing or
eye-catching. I always personally like
to use something like this. This is the
one that I use for like all my AI videos
if I ever create them. And it's good
because it highlights the word that it
speaks at that time. So it helps retain
your audience more because their eyes
kind of are fixated on that yellow word
that keeps popping up. So I'll show you
like this. Get ready to dive into the
fascinating world of sharks with five
incredible shark facts. So it just makes
it so much easier to read and just keeps
your actual viewer engaged watching at
all times. Now you do have all of these
to choose from. Some are free, some are
paid, so just keep an eye on that. But
look, there's over like a hundred
different captions you can choose. And
then down here, once you're happy with
your actual captions, I would go to
music. Now, again, all of this is free.
You've got hundreds and hundreds of
songs to choose from. They're all from
Tik Toks and Cap Cuts actual sound
library. And then I'm going to browse
through what we get from these nature
ones here. Usually the Majestic stuff's
quite good. So, go on to your video. And
then from here, we've got Get ready to
dive into the fascinating world of
sharks with five incredible shark facts
that will leave you speechless. from the
tiger shark's unique striped pattern. So
yeah, I'm happy. That's literally taken
me less than 10 minutes to create an
entire video from scratch. So Cap Cut
has now it's done the script, it's done
the voice over, it's done the scenes,
it's done the captions, and now it's
done the music all for free. All I've
got to do is click export there and
upload to my YouTube channel. That's all
I need to do. It's a 100% unique video.
Hasn't been done before. Now, like I
said, I will show you the actual
templates you can use to make shorts.
So, if we click back onto here, this uh
home button, scroll down here, and
you've got simplify creation with AI
templates. So, let's have a look at some
of these uh templates here, and we'll
pick which one we want to recreate. If
you don't believe in the power of
abundance, this me. So, that's like a
talking heads kind of Jesus message um
template. We've got Jurassic period
facts here. Hey there, dinosaur
enthusiasts. Welcome to our Jurassic
adventure. Let's meet five amazing
dinosaurs in a flash. So that was quite
cool. So that's all about like dinosaur
facts. Again, we have like an avatar one
here. Learn for lesson for success. I
wish I knew this when I was starting
out. The biggest mistakes in business.
So if you wanted to make a short space
channel on like motivational quotes,
this would be the one you want to go
for. So I'm going to go for Jurassic
period facts purely because I love
Jurassic Park. great film. Um, and those
kind of like dinosaur fact videos do
really well. So, if I just click remake
here, then we're going to get this
pop-up box here. So, Jurassic period
facts, create a video about. So, it's
obviously pre-filled out some of the
text here for us. We've got a bit of a
template. So, let's say I want five and
I want dinosaur. So, top five Jurassic
dinosaur facts that will blow your mind.
Now, as you can see, I'm not giving it
that much information, but it's going to
give us everything. So here you can see
it's creating the script, it's creating
the voice over and then it generates the
media for us. So that tiny bit of
information I've given it is going to
give us this entire thing for free
within like 2 minutes. Okay, so here we
go. This has just generated the entire
everything you see here has just been
done from that tiny bit of text I
inputed. So let's just give it a play
and see what it's given us. Hey there,
Dino enthusiasts. Ready for a
mind-blowing Jurassic journey? Let's
dive into five incredible dinosaur facts
that'll leave you in awe. First up, did
you know that some dinosaurs had
feathers? That's right. Recent
discoveries suggest that even the mighty
T-Rex might have sported some fluffy
plumage. Next, that's actually really
cool. Look, I know this is obviously AI
generated media. It's not as good as
what you see David Atenburgh make, but
it's scalable. So anyone of any skill
set can start up a brand new dinosaur
facts channel, make like 50 of these
within 10 minutes. Now you could go
through and change anything you see
here. So let's say I wanted to change
this like hello you dino enthusiasts or
I could change the voice over. I could
change the clips again. I could change
the background music. I could change the
actual like captions. So all of this has
been done for me. But I have the
complete capability and flexibility to
go in there and change whatever I like
to suit me, to suit my needs, to suit my
channel and all of that. So yeah, just
like that, anyone with any skill level
can create incredible AI videos for free
using this software. Now, for those of
you who prefer using computers when
editing software, I would recommend
downloading the Capka app, which can be
used on both Windows and Apple. But for
those of you like me who actually prefer
editing on the web, just go directly to
the official website as the software is
ready to use instantly. And finally, for
those of you who actually enjoy
capturing short videos on your phones
and doing quick edits, download Cap
Cut's mobile app. It's so convenient and
full of all that create anytime,
anywhere capabilities. So, thank you
very much for watching. Hope you enjoyed
it. See you next one. Goodbye.